<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./cellformatter.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>XLS Cell Formatter</name>
    
  	<shortDescription>
       The XLS Cell Formatter changes certain cell-level formatting options of selected cells, such as text alignment, rotation, and text format.
   	</shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
	       The XLS Cell Formatter changes certain cell-level formatting options of selected cells, such as text alignment, rotation, and text format.<p />
	       This node defines a formatting instruction only which needs to be written to an xlsx file via the <i>XLS Formatter (apply)</i> node subsequently.
    	</intro>
    	
		<tab name="Tag Selection">
            <option name="applies to tag (single tag only)">Tag in your input table for which the formatting of this node should be applied to. </option>
  		</tab>
        
        <tab name="Text Position and Format">
            <option name="horizontal alignment">Pick the horizontal alignment of your text in the respective cell (e.g. left, center, right). </option>
            <option name="vertical alignment">Pick the vertical alignment of your text in the respective cell (e.g. top, middle, bottom). </option>
            <option name="text rotation angle">Set the angle by which your text in the cell should be rotated.</option>
            <option name="word wrap">Select whether long text shall be wrapped to new lines within cells.</option>
            <option name="text format">Define the text format of you cell (e.g. percent: 0.00% , whole number: #,##0, ...). Please use only English locale values, irrespective of your target or local environment.</option>
        </tab>        

    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Control Table">XLS Control Table holding tags that define which cells of the sheet to format.</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Optional XLS Formatter">The XLS Formatter input port potentially holding previous formatting instructions that the instructions of this node shall be added to.</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="XLS Formatter">The XLS Formatter output port holding the collected formatting instructions including the added formatting information from this node.</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
