<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./conditionalformatter.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>XLS Conditional Formatter</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
       The XLS Conditional Formatter node defines the instruction for your spreadsheet application to color cell backgrounds according to their numeric value. 
   	</shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
	       The XLS Conditional Formatter node defines instruction for your spreadsheet application to color cell backgrounds according to their numeric value.<p />
	       This node defines a formatting instruction only which needs to be written to an xlsx file via the <i>XLS Formatter (apply)</i> node subsequently.
    	</intro>
            
        <tab name="Tag Selection">
            <option name="applies to tag (single tag only)">Tag in your input table for which the formatting of this node should be applied to. </option>
  		</tab>
        
        <tab name="Conditional Formatting Settings">
            <option name="Mid scale point needed?">Set this option if you want to create a three level coloring scheme. </option>
            <option name="min">Set the lower bound for the coloring in the conditional formatter. The corresponding color will be displayed for all values smaller or equal than this threshold.</option>
            <option name="min color">Select the color using the color pane.</option>
            <option name="mid">Set the middle scaling point for the coloring in the conditional formatter.</option>
            <option name="mid color">Select the color using the color pane.</option>
            <option name="max">Set the upper bound for the coloring in the conditional formatter. The corresponding color will be displayed for all values greater or equal than this threshold.</option>
            <option name="max color">Select the color using the color pane.</option>
        </tab>        

    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Control Table">XLS Control Table holding tags that define which cells of the sheet to format.</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Optional XLS Formatter">The XLS Formatter input port potentially holding previous formatting instructions that the instructions of this node shall be added to.</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="XLS Formatter">The XLS Formatter output port holding the collected formatting instructions including the added formatting information from this node.</outPort>
    </ports>    

</knimeNode>
