<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./cellmerger.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>XLS Cell Merger</name>
    
   	<shortDescription>
	       The XLS Cell Merger node merges the cells for given ranges of input tags. 
   	</shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
	       The XLS Cell Merger node merges the cells for given ranges of input tags.<p />
	       Tags in the provided XLS Control Table must appear in rectangular ranges. A single tag may re-appear, as long as two ranges of the same tag share at most a cell's corner, but not a cell's border. In this case, multiple ranges will be added based on the same tag.<p />
	       Optionally, all distinct tags can be used instead of a single one (see below).   
    	</intro>
    	
        <tab name="Tag Selection">
            <option name="applies to tag (single tag only)">Tag in your XLS Control Table that defines the merge range(s).</option>
        	<option name="applies to all tags">Instead of specifying a single tag, the Cell Merger is applied repetitively to all distinct tags found in the control table. Note that in this case, no comma-separated tag list splitting is applied but the full cell content qualifies as a tag.<p />
				This option	eases definition of adjacent merge ranges based on the original data table's values.</option>
		</tab>       

    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Control Table">XLS Control Table holding tags that define which parts of the sheet shall be merged.</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Optional XLS Formatter">The XLS Formatter input port potentially holding previous formatting instructions that the instructions of this node shall be added to.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="XLS Formatter">The XLS Formatter output port holding the collected formatting instructions including the added formatting information from this node.</outPort>
    </ports>
     

</knimeNode>
