<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./sheetproperties.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>XLS Sheet Properties</name>
    
   	<shortDescription>
       The XLS Sheet Properties node changes sheet properties, such as freeze, auto-filter, hidden columns, or hidden rows.
   	</shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
	       	The XLS Sheet Properties node changes sheet properties, such as freeze, auto-filter, hidden columns, or hidden rows.<p />
       		
       		This node defines a formatting instruction only which needs to be written to an xlsx file via the <i>XLS Formatter (apply)</i> node subsequently.
    	</intro>
    	    
        <tab name="Tag Selection">
            <option name="applies to tag (single tag only)">Tag in your input table for which the formatting of this node should be applied to. </option>
  		</tab>
        
        <tab name="Sheet Properties">
			<option name="freeze sheet at tagged cell">Freeze your sheet at a specific cell (more precisely: at its top-left corner) identified via a tag in the control table. Note that the tag may occur more than once in the control table. In this case, the top-left-most occurrence is used.</option>
			<option name="set auto-filter for tagged cell range">Set an auto-filter for a range based on a single rectangular range of a matching tag in the control table.</option>
			<option name="hide columns of tagged cells">Hide the columns from your sheet based on a matching tag in any of the columns' cells.</option>
			<option name="hide rows of tagged cells">Hide the rows from your sheet based on a matching tag in any of the rows' cells.</option>
        </tab>      

    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Control Table">XLS Control Table holding tags that define which cells of the sheet to format.</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Optional XLS Formatter">The XLS Formatter input port potentially holding previous formatting instructions that the instructions of this node shall be added to.</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="XLS Formatter">The XLS Formatter output port holding the collected formatting instructions including the added formatting information from this node.</outPort>
    </ports>    

</knimeNode>
